okay I think we believe that we are all
good so uh we can start the
lecture uh okay so this lecture is on uh
visual imitation so in the last lecture
you learned
about uh demonstrations learning from
demonstration but in the style which is
called Behavior C cling which is
teleoperation so essentially you make
the robot go through a series of motions
under where the human is dictating all
the
choices and uh that's that's a pretty
popular approach today so Behavior
cloning using diffusion policy so I
talked about this two lectures ago now
this is not the way uh a child can
learn right because an adult can not
control the activations of the neurons
of the child's brain so as to get the
child to lift up her hands in exactly
the right way and so on so that is a
mode that we have used for teaching
robots but it is
not parallel to anything which we have
with how children acquire Knowledge from
adults so today what I'm going to do is
to talk about visual imitation in the
way it actually works in humans and how
we can draw upon that for robots
Okay so uh so I need to remind you of uh
this philosophical slide which I've used
uh in the beginning of the lecture as
well which is an idea which goes back to
Alan Turing 1950 which is that uh we
can we can train a child uh or we
whether we not we like it a child gets
trained over time and develops and
becomes an intelligent human being by
the at at some point in time and can we
emulate that process for robots or for
AIS and this was turing's proposal that
instead of trying to produce a program
to simulate the adult mind why not
produce one which simulates the child
and then subjected to an appropriate
course of Education now in this Spirit
there are there are insights that we can
get from Child Development and this is a
paper review paper from Smith and gaser
which has some insights on how children
learn and how children uh start out with
some background knowledge when they're
born they already have some and then
these these aspects multimodality
incremental learning meaning training
for hierarchies physical meaning act in
the world explore be social use language
so I've highlighted be social social
here means learning from others so this
is obviously essential for language
language is always learned from some
community that you are part of but
social learning is also how we acquire
skills so if you look at modern society
and for example industrial
manufacturer okay how
how do we know know how to make a a car
right how do you assemble a car I mean
there these are all these are not
processes that one individual develops
these are processes which have developed
over time and space and we have a way of
communicating them across across
Generations across peers from parents to
child etc etc so this is what what we
are after capturing so you have to S of
imagine that you know 5 million years
ago there were these ancestors of modern
humans roaming around in the Savana in
Africa and somebody developed a clever
way to make a tool and uh so what he or
she did was to quickly communicate it to
to uh to all his friends and then so
that tribe became a little bit smarter
and so on and so forth okay so uh so how
do we do uh so let's uh Let's uh try to
capture this idea of visual immitation
and I'm going to do this with an Works
in just the right time okay and
uh this this lecture is going to be in
two parts the first part is going to be
about uh Locomotion and navigation and
the second part is about manipulation
and in both cases what I'm trying to do
is how do we do social learning learning
from
others and I'm going to start with this
example which is uh 2018 so this is now
actually 6 years old and uh uh the the
basic idea is the father right okay so
think of all these tasks okay all these
capabilities that humans have various
and all of this you can find YouTube's
videos on YouTube and we want to make
our robot do this so what is that
classical way that Boston Dynamics you
have to think of as the leading company
building human at that time like the
atlas was the leading humanoid in 2018
uh how would you train an atlas to do
these tasks so how they would do it is
they would design they would sit down
and think hard and design a controller
with the MPC okay or you might say okay
the Revolutionary idea would be let's do
reinforcement learning but good luck
right I mean uh the number of Trials you
would need to manage to succeed to do a
cartwheel is uh is imens so somehow we
want to find a way of using uh uh using
all this data and and the promise here
obviously is there's huge amounts of
data on YouTube and can we use this data
to train your humanoid to do any of
these actions so what are we going to
do so uh so there was at that time
already some preceding context which was
a deep reinforcement learning based
motion
imitation so this deep mimic paper okay
uh so uh so this is now this is the the
world of computer Graphics actually as
much as the world of uh robotics so in
computer Graphics they have to animate
characters right and they have different
ways of doing it one way of doing it is
that an artist draws each uh in each
frame the pose of the character and
another way which has been going on for
some time is moap moap means that you
collect you have humans who have some
sensors on their body and then you you
have some setup where you have multiple
cameras detecting Those sensors and then
you can essentially get the sequence of
joint angles over time and you use that
so this is a way to economize on the
work of the uh of the the animator makes
the job of that and they used to be 20
years ago there used to be these debates
where there were people uh like uh who
said oh we don't do motion capture that
sort of in a way degrading that's just
copying human motion we have artists who
are creative and who are going to do it
all all themselves so U those debates
are all kind of tired because everybody
uses motion capture to some extent okay
and then uh uh okay so we have recorded
joint angles now we then do
reinforcement learning to make this uh
robot do all this okay so just think of
what do you think are the steps which
are needed here and what what is what
that makes this problem interesting as
opposed to just tral you could just say
we have all the motion of the human just
the robot does exactly the same
thing it's because the robot's body is
not the same as the human body that's a
very key issue so this is the
retargeting problem the the the size and
shape of the human body is different
from the robot's body okay if the robot
is going to perform all those actions in
physical space then they have to be
correct for the body of the
robot okay so that's problem one uh so
uh so therefore uh so then what use is
this so then what use is the the data
that you have collected humans so we are
going to have to do reinforcement
learning in a simulator reinforcement
learning in a simulator ensures that
what you're going to learn is physically
plausible I mean at least it's plausible
in simulation then you have to solve the
same to real problem but uh but the body
is
different so retargeting doesn't solve
the problem of it being physically
consistent so what you do is the the
idea is that and there's maybe some task
like hit Target so the key Insight is
that uh first of all we're going to get
rid of this motion capture and of course
this is where the power of computer
vision is going to come in but that's
that's just makes it convenient and now
you suddenly have access to huge amounts
of data but the central problem is is
there is retargeting needed because
there are different bodies but
retargeting is not enough because you
need it to be physically consistent
so what you do is you you you convert
the human video into something for the
robot to copy at every frame of time it
will not copy it exactly so the Insight
is the following so suppose if there's a
child if I'm a teacher I'm a coach and
you are a student and you trying to copy
what I'm doing you're going to try to
copy if I do this I mean like suppose
you go to a yoga class I mean I mean
that's a good example you go to a yoga
class and you try to copy the teacher
you will try to imitate in your body
okay and you will not succeed but you
have a reference for every moment in
time so that's what we are trying to do
so at every moment in time now you've
got a reference pose which is that of
the human so what's the benefit of that
in reinforcement learning the challenge
is always that of it being a
a a sparse reward I mean you you do a
whole bunch of stuff and at the end
either you win the chess game or you
don't win the chess game and now
suddenly it's become dense reward
because at every frame you are saying be
kind of like your teacher or coach so
the so it is a reinforcement learning
problem there's no way avoid to avoid
the search there is a search which is
needed in terms of in action space which
is is exactly what talks to apply at
every joint you're not getting out of
that okay so it is a reinforcement
learning problem then the search
inherent and reinforcement learning
cannot be avoided what you are
benefiting from is that instead of a
sparse reward at the end you get a dense
reward at every frame at every frame you
try to copy the post that's it that's
the key idea and uh and we did this by
using HMR which is anu's work
uh and let's see some examples of how
well it
worked and you know people are they
versions of this idea I mean like
there's a recent set of stuff out of
Stanford but which is 2024 but I think
we did all this in
2018 okay
uh uh okay so so this is the human video
and then we convert it to uh we we 3D f
it and so this is the computer vision
part of the problem and then and then
now this becomes a series of dense
rewards for the robot to to
copy so so always when you're going to
do visual imitation a lot of information
is missing you only observe the external
kinematics you do not know the internal
forces talks and so forth you do not
know the
intentions all of that is missing goals
intentions and uh forces and talks all
of that are missing so those have to be
guessed so therefore it always has to be
in the context of some uh physics
simulator and some kind of a
reinforcement learning
algorithm okay but uh but but now you
have a you have a policy which is
physically valid so you you can put it
on different environments and check for
robustness so here are just like more
examples that you could do it for just
not one motion but many
motions
okay okay I also want to tell you uh I
mean just since behavior cloning is with
t op is so popular these days do you
think that you can teach your robot to
do this by Behavior
cloning no right okay so I'll rest my
case because this is the most popular
technique these days
so
okay and I think it didn't work on
Gangam Style right Andre if
you're yeah the perception part it would
work today
I
see so it couldn't
train
yeah okay okay so now now you so so so
this is it gives you a demonstration of
how visual imitation could work and
there are variations of this so there
are aspects of this problem which are
easier in the second lecture I'm going
to talk about manipulation and
manipulation is much harder because you
have to Now operate in contact with an
object and that makes life more
difficult so in here we are dealing with
movements in free
space and uh but for this there a very
natural approach okay so now I want to
give you a little bit of background on
the underlying computer vision technique
and this is a problem on which we have
worked on for years or the computer
vision Community has worked for decades
and in particular worked for 25 years
and finally with this paper we claim
that we have solved this problem
okay so uh so first let's understand the
setup so the setup is that if you have
an A a single frame with people uh
that's a 2d XY observation now what we
can do is to lift it to 3D right that's
when we are doing it so that would be XY
Z but in fact the original data is three
d as well but that's 3D in a different
way which is x y and time because you
have a
video okay so if you put these two ideas
together that you lift every person to
3D and they are moving in time then what
does that correspond to that's
4D so so what we our goal is that we
have humans moving around in space and
time and we we we infer the true state
so the true state is this four
dimensional
okay so how do we do it so this is the
paper from last year uh and uh uh the I
I have to give you some more background
as to the techniques for this so the
techniques go back to this earlier paper
from 2018 which is HMR
1.0 and uh
the key thing here is that we have to
have a model for the person so how do we
think about the so so normally computer
vision people like dealing with rigid
objects a whole lot of the theory of
structure for motion is based on Rigid
objects seen from multiple cameras
humans are distinctly non- rigid we have
all these body parts and we have the the
joints are going to be various angles
and so on so a priori this problem feels
totally hopeless like how are we going
to solve this problem because a
structure from motion is hard enough
from reconstruct from multiple views
here you you you have maybe only a
single View and uh and the object is non
rigid okay so what is going to save you
what's going to save you is essentially
top down knowledge top down knowledge of
the structure of the human body so let
us for the moment assume that all of us
are identically shaped so you have
exactly so if you have one unit of size
for your head then the full body is
eight units or 7.5 units there is the
this old picture of the Vitruvian man
that Leonardo popularized where the
artists know this right so the different
portions of the body are have a certain
ratio to each other it's slightly
different for men and women it slightly
different for kids versus adults but
we're going to handwave about this a
little bit
okay so so what we have then is a uh if
you just consider the skeleton we have a
certain number of degrees of freedom
which are all the joint angles okay so
that we are going to capture in this
term pose so pose is all the joint
angles shape here is going to deal with
essentially are you thin are you plump
are you tall are you uh you know a child
male female so those variations are
dealt with in this shape space and
essentially the way you construct the
shape space is that you have
measurements on lots of humans and then
you do some kind of a principal
component
analysis okay and and then of course you
have this viewed by a camera and let's
say we used a scaled orthography project
assumption so there's a rotation and
translation of the camera with respect
to the human and then the scaling Factor
essentially captures how far away the
person is with respect to the camera
okay so uh so that's the so we have now
reduced the number of degrees of freedom
it's become a finite problem because
it's all of these are a small set of
numbers like 50 numbers or 70 numbers or
whatever and uh now uh what is the what
is the signal for this so the signal for
this is going to be if uh how do I do
the Reconstruction in 2D I can find the
key points so in 2D I can locate the
left elbow right elbow left shoulder
right shoulder Etc and uh what we know
is that the 3D positions of the joint
should be such that when you project
them in the image they should be
consistent with the 2D projections so
this is what's called reprojection loss
this is a standard term in computer
vision uh so popularized from the
structure from motion work structure
from motion slam all of this is about
finding a 3D positions of points such
that the repr ejection error is
minimized
okay uh so that's that's the indicated
by this so you have a 3D model you
project it in the image and then the 2D
key points have to line
up okay uh okay you do this in a
straightforward way and you get these
horrible
reconstructions so these reconstructions
are monsters of some sort but what is
true about these monsters is that they
uh if you look at just the projections
of those key points they are actually
correct so the 3D uh the 3D key points
of these monsters when projected to the
image are are accurate they lie in the
right 2D key points so what has happened
is that you walked off the manifold
there's a manifold of what valid human
shapes are and you walked off from it so
what do we need to do okay so this is
again these are techniques from that
time so there's Deja here at that time
if you want to check that are you is it
consistent the way you would do this is
to use some kind of a gan so again would
say would there would be a discriminator
which would say are you off the human
manifold or are you not and you should
be on the human
manifold so uh okay so there you have
the discriminator and that's going to
check whether you are on the manifold of
human shapes and how do you train that
so for this you need genuine 3D data but
you need only a small amount of it so
that you are capturing the shapes of
true humans and the uh and the the the
reprojection error you uh that
constraint can be exploited on General
images right because you and you want
those because those will capture humans
in a variety of poses with occlusion
with objects etc etc so and you can get
millions of images and and for this this
the Machinery is uh modern computer
vision knows what to do it you hire a
bunch of people they sit somewhere and
you click points left elbow right elbow
left shoulder right shoulder and uh okay
it's painful but if you're a big company
you have a budget for such things and
once you've collected a million images
you you you you have the training data
so computer vision today the big
successes of computer vision are really
all successes not a big data
maybe it is a success of big data but
really a big
supervision
okay uh okay uh so you okay blah blah
blah okay so then then you what do we do
more recently we essentially just took
it to scale you have lot more data you
have a more powerful model you have used
a Transformer of course now and then uh
and then you and then you have you work
hard
and then and then okay so that's one
part of the story the second part of the
story which actually is very very
important is that in the real world if
you want to do 4D reconstructions you
are going to have to deal with images or
video with many people so therefore you
have to solve the tracking problem okay
the tracking problem has existed from
the early days of computer vision it
really goes back actually to before
computer vision in radar and so on so
radar was invented around World War II
and used very successful invol War to so
you have enemy aircraft coming in you
want to detect them you want to track
them and then you want to have your uh
your strategy okay so then there were
versions of this for images and video
and so on now uh we want to if you have
some video with many people you want to
track each person and you want to know
the identity that okay person a match to
a prime in the next frame and so on so
uh again huge literature but the
important Insight here is that if you do
this with 3D features it's going to be
much better and what are the 3D features
we can think of so we can think of
appearance we can think of pose uh we
can think of location okay so let me uh
maybe show the this idea why we want to
do tracking in 3D rather than in 2D
so uh let's see if this demo you
okay okay so in 2D this is what happens
right when objects move they can occlude
each other from the perspective of a
camera but what happens in 3D in
3D nobody is ever occluded they always
exist so my slogan for this is normally
out of sight is out of
mind when somebody disapp appears behind
a tree they're out of sight but in 3D
you all the identities are always there
out of sight is not out of mind people
are are always there in this
three-dimensional world so if your
representation is a threedimensional
representation then these people never
disappear they're always there they they
only disappear in a 2d projection in the
3D world nothing nothing bad has
happened to
them okay that's one insight
second Insight is uh what how tracking
works is essentially that you're going
to do some kind of matching of
features and matching of features
traditionally meant matching of pixel
values so consider this one guy who's
this is I think some rugby player and
you have four different poses of this
fellow okay if you look at it at the and
let's look at the neighborhood of his uh
right shoulder that's indicated by that
Target point
if you think of it in in 2D in pixel
space the appearance is changing a lot
right if you think of it in 3D okay so
we looking at that
point and in 3D how do I think about it
in 3D the way I should think about it is
that there is a texture map on of his
body which corresponds to like the color
of his skin the color of his clothes etc
etc so so there is a there is a on the
mesh of the body here what's the color
it's like the color of my sweater and
what's the color here it's the color of
my skin and so on and that as I move
around doesn't change whereas the 2D
appearance is changing
constantly so so therefore you you need
to do that so you need to have anyway
let me go back to that slide which now
gives the tracking algorithm so the
tracking algorithm essentially says we
recover the 3D pose we recover the 3D
locations of the key points we recover
the appearance which is going to be a
texture map on the body of the person
and now as you so now you project from
time T to t + one so the movement of the
person okay you just use a local linear
approximation pose you can have a
learned model on how the pose changes
and the appearance you just model as
constant because my I'm not changing my
clothing every 130th of a second
and uh and that's it so by just uh going
to 3D we have made the problem uh easier
but it requires the tracking problem
becomes easier but it requires doing the
lifting to 3D and here I'm going to make
a meta remark a lot of Robotics will
benefit from using 3D computer vision
rather than 2D computer vision and and
this is like a general remark which I
think will it will play out in the next
few years so many of these robotics
tasks where they're using 2D images if
they use 3D information they would just
be much more natural there would be
invariances built in and so on but
that's a small editorial remark anyway
so this is meant to show that the
tracking
works and uh and then this is the the
proof of the pudding which is uh that we
can do reconstructions so up in the top
left you see the raw video and in the
bottom you see the the reconstruct
now what is noteworthy here is everybody
can do 3D reconstructions the question
is can you really do 3D reconstruction
and the test is does the technique work
when there are many people cluding each
other does your Technique work when the
poses are
unusual okay uh because just
straightforward standing person anybody
can do that so the test was unusual
poses and dealing with crowded people
crowding because of multiple people
objects Etc so this is what we can
do so here the Reconstruction is frame
by frame
[Music]
so this is the unusual po so you can
there people who claim that they have
good reconstruction algorithm the test
is of this
I I mean I could go on forever but I
think I want to show the next uh dance
sequence because uh I've had people work
on this for 25 years
this is being done Same by
frame this is the test that you don't
get confused by multiple people and so
on
okay I think I'll stop here okay uh okay
so what are the next steps so uh so in
fact the previous the paper sfv was
based on the previous version of HMR so
I think now we are we have better
technology and uh the half life of any
computer vision St of the art model is
about 6 months so normally in 6 months
whatever you claim is State ofth art
gets beaten by somebody this paper I
think we are at what one and a half
years what is it
ano yeah but we I mean we had done it of
course before that right we submitted so
as of yet it's still not it is still
state of that okay so which uh by our
community standards is is is a record
okay okay what are the next steps okay
so now let me see what we can do with
this
yeah
uh the answer is yes of course but but
the point here is to show what you can
do with a single frame because sometimes
you have to process just a single frame
so temporal smoothing can always I mean
always whenever you have a more
sophisticated model it should do better
for you I mean yeah and and it opens up
a whole lot of other problems like uh
not problems but actually opportunities
like prediction and so on but I'm I'm
not going to get into that here right
now so first I want to show that this
idea of learning from video is not just
in simulation so that work was just in
simulation but it's like 2018 so the
more recent work is that we can actually
use this for training real humanoids and
this is work led by
Ilia and so here is a robot walking
around in San
Francisco so this is the digit robot
which is a it's a headless
humanoid it has no vision it's blind
[Music]
okay and then oh yeah let's have this
video
to so I mean all the walking robot
people they have to show that it walks
in different terrains and then if you
poke at it with the stick doesn't fall
so so these are the kind of demos that
you need to
see and
uh
okay okay how so what's a Machinery so
this is now proof that this is a real
robot working in the real world and uh
uh there I won't get into the details
here but there is a Transformer based
policy and uh it's been trained with a
whole lot of trajectories and the
trajectories are derived from multiple
sources so the trajectories could come
from a previously trained neural network
policy trained with reinforcement
learning could come from uh MP based
controller that the manufacturer
supplies it could come from motion
capture moap data or from internet
videos and and uh uh so these are just
examples of the different sources of
data but uh so this is like an example
of the uh data from humans so this is uh
so we we have like so this video of this
person walking and now you use that for
training this robot let's see if that
shown here so what problem do we have to
solve first here this is so this is
going to generate a fake trajectory
basically where you have copied the so
the human movement into the uh into the
robots movement so you have to solve the
retargeting problem so retargeting
always
involves in some kind of Correspondence
and imposing some constraints and this
is a problem that has to be dealt with
for full body robots that humanoids and
it has to be dealt with for the hand
case because the human hand is not going
to be identical to the robot hand so the
retargeting problem is always with you
and you people typically solve it by
some kind of human intervention so the
human identifies correspondences or
fingers or joints or what have you okay
and then the other aspect is that the
the training
procedure so the training procedure has
to deal with incomplete data so I
already alluded to that in the SF work
that you do not know information about
forces and talks and so on you right you
do not know the goals and intentions so
goals and intentions get translated to
actions so when the so what did the
human actually want to do what joint
angle did the humans motor cortex and
cerebelum command and then what did the
joints deliver there's a gap between
what you want which is determined by
your your brain and what is actually
delivered which is the the muscular
skeletal system so all of that is a
problem so in the in the previous yes
SFP example that was being dealt with by
reinforcement learning that you you just
made it into a dense reward situation
here the Machinery is different so the
Machinery here is next token prediction
but with missing data so some tokens are
missing and you have to try to deal with
that and and that's that's what is the
trick
here okay so uh so I so I think the
future is is actually quite bright
because
uh for these whole body motion of
humanoids and I I could have brought
more contemporary papers I think I would
cite work from say shalong uh vings
group at UCSD where they've done various
kinds of imitation uh for robots dancing
and so on so I think I think the role of
imitation learning for uh for humanoids
is here to stay I I think the the basic
methodology works
I want to now uh uh turn to something
more abstract and which is to say that
we can learn from human
videos at many levels of abstraction and
there's this beautiful slide I got from
sorab Gupta which I agree with fully so
therefore I thought I would steal his
slide rather than make it myself okay so
there's a lowest level of uh uh of where
you can compare robots and humans which
is uh muscle tensions in the human and
torqus in the
motors okay then there are macro actions
right like take one step forward then uh
macro actions might be joint angle
changes skills skills might be walking
running picking
up uh tearing something uh throwing you
know so
on uh then goals
and the sub goals and goals so what you
have is when you see a video of a human
human or humans performing actions in
some sense you have some signal for all
of
these and you can try to aail of that
for robots at any of these levels right
so these are just levels of abstraction
because all human behavior is
hierarchical so robot behavior is also
hierarchical and you can use information
at any of these
levels so what should I do let me move
this stupid thing
out
so depending on so we can use so uh
there's an embodiment Gap right the body
of the robot is not the same as the body
of the human but it may not it doesn't
matter with respect to goals right so
the more the you can you can
essentially get the benefit of visual
imitation at different levels of this
hierarchy and when you do it at a More
abstracted Level the body of the robot
is no longer so much of a problem okay
and then I want to show you examples
of a paper we did uh okay so there's the
lower level of the skill
okay okay so this is a actually a paper
from our lab from from
2019 okay and uh so this is uh we we
have let's say a video of humans walking
around in some
environment right okay and I want to
learn from this for a robot walking
around okay and the robot in this case
was a wheel robot and the human
obviously is walking around so the
lowlevel you know joint angle command
for the human
legs Translating that into robot wheel
commands silly right it doesn't make
sense so you don't want to be doing the
transfer at the lower
level so what is the what can you do
here but you can do a transfer at a mid
level and a higher level because when
you walk around what are the insights
that you have here when you look at this
look at that picture at the bottom what
is that and now you will see the next
steps of the human walking through it it
basically tell you that this is open
space through which you can go this is a
door to which you can go this is the
concept of an affordance going back to
Gibson so affordance is how you can
interact with an object or some aspect
of the
environment so essentially we
are what is being revealed here is the
affordance of a door which when a human
is walking through that space you have
that
okay okay then you also acquire
essentially sub
routines or operators or some when we
walk what do we do we tend to do like if
I when I walk out of that door into this
classroom what am I going to do very
likely I'm going to turn right when we
come out of a door we often turn left or
we turn right this is a St stereotype
behavior and if you have lots of videos
of humans uh navigating around in a
space with egocentric cameras you will
you will have that in the data so
essentially what I'm saying is that you
can operate at one higher level of
abstraction not the level of abstraction
which is take one step forward or one
step to the left or one step to the
right you can operate at the level of go
a few steps in the direction in which
you're heading or turn to to the right
or turn to the left
so so uh there's a nice coupling here
because the affordance is what can you
do and the sub routine is how what do
you do okay and we can learn this so if
you turn left you get this story you
turn right so this is what the so what
we had was that the robot learned these
these sub
routines and uh
uh so uh so let's say what we did so
there's a robot interacting with an
environment and we want this robot
interacting with an environment and then
uh we have first person videos from
walking
people okay so how do we make use of
this and we are going
to this Machinery at the end is going to
give us two two two things one is an
affordance model which is which which in
this case translates to what sub rutine
to use where okay afforded models are
going to play a major role with object
manipulation okay and if you think that
this is a trivial problem I uh commend
to you the problem that you face when
you go to a new hotel in a new country
and you cannot figure out how to get the
hot and cold to work properly I mean
because every country I go to and every
Hotel I go to they have a different way
of sort of how to get the hot and cold
water and you and you have to figure get
out the affordances of this particular
shower system before you manage to get
scalded right or when you approach a
door I mean canonical example some knobs
have to be turned to the right some
knobs have to be turned to the left some
cases it's like knob that you have to
push some cases it has to be pulled so
we as adults have trouble with this so
just imagine a 2-year-old child right I
mean so affordances are a thing we in
the world we live in there is a process
by which we acquire the specialist
knowledge of how to operate on an object
or interact with an environment
yeah they all emerge with learning
yeah when your model like chooses sub to
use you have a of how many sub is like
five or 10 or something yeah yeah I not
going to go I I'll have one or two
slides with the Gory details the uh the
the the details this is 2019 we can do
this much more fancy now with all the
tools we have today but the core ideas
of this I actually was just reminded of
it because I Was preparing this lecture
are are pretty good even if I say so
myself
okay uh okay so what are the details
okay yeah so the details are there video
and uh and then we did one more trick
which is that a video will be a series
of images and you want to figure out the
action what is the action associated
with this so it turns out that you can
do this with a little bit of interaction
data and this is itself a good principle
when a child learns most of what the
child May learn maybe through
observation but observation is passive
you are not performing the action
someone else is performing the action
and then there is interaction which is
different from observation interaction
is I do stuff in my body so when I pick
up this object it's in my body right as
opposed to you picking up this bottle
and I get more information when I pick
up the bottle the difference is my own
life is going to be like 10,000 hours
and uh the life of others is 156 million
hours on YouTube so you need to find a
judicious way of using a small amount of
interaction data and and lot more
observation data okay so here this is
the observation of a video but what we
can do is we can actually if a robot
actually moves through an
environment then uh then the robot knows
its own commands so you can essentially
get a label of the actions so you can
then say given these two images can I
predict what was the action that I took
right so I can pseudo label this and and
this is not a surprise because if you
think of it from a computer vision
perspective you are moving through a
space so structure promotion would tell
you what is a movement that you did for
the change of image but you can actually
learn it with in a do it in a learning
style as well okay so you essentially
can do uh uh so so you with the help of
this little model that you train on
interaction data now you can take all
this video and you can pseudo label it
with actions that you uh that you uh
that that were going on in this person
and the actions are in this case go
straight turn left turn right okay okay
and now now you throw some learning mumo
jumbo on top which is that you're going
to learn
simultaneously uh these set of sub
routines which is like a small number of
sub routines and then you're going to
learn an affordance model which tells
you what is applicable
where yeah
yeah and uh and that's and that's what
we did uh okay I'm not going to go into
the details so this is all 20 but this
these are the sub routines which are
discovered so let's see what the video
says so this
is so the so this sub routin is is
basically one sub routin discovers
turning right one discovers turning left
one discovers going straight and so on
and then
uh and then uh and then now you can do
hierarchical RL right so suppose you
want to do you have a goal like go to
some point which is uh uh 47 m Northwest
for example now uh so you have the usual
navigation task you go to some geometric
goal you go to find some television or
whatever but all of those you can you
can operate at the lowest level if
you're do RL or you can operate with
these more abstracted approaches and and
and it turns out I mean the obligatory
in all of these things you always have
some picture where there is some RL
training curve and with whatever was
your clever idea the curve should be
rising higher and quicker and sure
enough we have something like that okay
but again I think the technology of this
is 2018 2019 but the key ideas actually
should transfer to manipulation which is
uh acquiring an affordance model and
acquiring sub routines acquiring sub
routines by the way is is to me a a
major uh interesting and scientific
challenge in
robotics because I I think that the
future is not in end to endend training
for every skill that is not a scalable
solution you need to have hierarchies
and the benefit of hierarchies is is
that you can get reusable skills right
this walking straight is beneficial if
my goal is to go to the airport and it's
also beneficial if my goal is to go to
the water font I can still I can use the
sub routine whereas if I did endtoend
training for each of these tasks it
would not help
us uh so uh and uh finally I cannot
resist make a dig and language which is
this is visual imitation so uh
you and now we humans always can
communicate uh so so how does a parent
teach a child so the parent can teach a
child they do use language I'm not
denying that but uh there are certain
abilities which are much better done by
visual example than by words and if you
don't believe me read the set of
instructions on how to climb a
staircase okay while I drink my water
you should check it out it's it's true
it's from the juliia Julio
coresa so you can do all this or you can
just time St
don't you want to explain an a spin you
just you do it by visual example you
don't convert it to this hundreds of
words okay so now let's take a five
minute break I I was very leisurely so I
think you do not need a 10-minute break
just a five minute break will do okay we
can
start okay so uh this half of the
lecture is going to be or this is
lecture 8 B is going to be about visual
imitation but in the context of
manipulation and this is a harder
problem than Locomotion and
navigation okay okay so uh so let me uh
again start with a Berkeley Centric
account of this so uh so this is a
picture which shows what uh we might
want to do so imagine that you have the
this this scene so there is like
somebody doing some stuff in a kitchen
and uh and what you want to do is
reconstruct the hand in 3D reconstruct
the object in
3D and uh and this is this is a paper
from like four years ago now which was
which showed how to do this uh it this
is a hard problem and this is not a Sol
problem so while I consider consider
reconstructing the whole body to be more
or less a solve problem
reconstructing the hand and in
particular the object uh is not quite a
solve problem I mean we have made
progress but there is uh there is some
more years of work left on this problem
and I think that this will be very
impactful because currently a lot of the
techniques that are being used by people
they are basically 2D techniques
and 2D techniques make sense if the 3D
fication doesn't work but once the 3D
fication works then then I think that
often working in 3D is going to turn out
to be the right thing to do but let's
see what we can do
today okay so the there's the part of
reconstructing the hand in 3D and
there's a part of reconstructing the
object in 3D so the part of
reconstructing the hand in 3D I think we
have we have a lot of progress now and
this is a p paper from earlier this year
uh which was presented at cvpr and let
me show you the results again with a
video so again what are what is it that
we are looking for in order to be
impressed or not be impressed uh I there
should be a wide variety of poses that
you can deal with there should be the
fact that the the if the hand is
partially occluded or the hand is
manipulating an object then the
Reconstruction should still work
and here we are just looking at the
Reconstruction of the hand not the
object and I'll come to that in a second
you move this along a bit
so it's again a frame by frame
so here you see object interaction
right e
so when you see flicker that's an
indication that is uncertain because
neighboring PLS
are slightly differ so this gives you
some sense of the noise
okay okay so this is what we can do with
hands I think there is room here to do
some more work it's not I don't think
this problem is fully solved there will
be there will be room to do a bit better
I think uh but uh oh first the numbers
which show that this works well I I find
this boring but you have to show
this okay uh
okay uh oh yeah this is like a standard
kind of slide which shows which is you
find always in computer vision papers uh
what do you need somebody would say oh
do you need big data or do you need a
big model and the answer is both and
it's it's been the same answer always
for some years so that's a slide which
shows that if you just had more data uh
then the performance would be so much if
you had just a bigger model the
performance would be so much you you
need more data more more bigger model
and
uh uh various okay okay so now what I
want to show is what can we do for
objects so the hand reconstruction
problem we have made substantial
progress but we are maybe at the 80%
Point not not 100% okay now there is the
object reconstruction problem where
maybe we are at the 50% Point okay so we
have lot more to do so what can we do
today okay so that's what we'll show
you uh so uh so what you're trying to do
is to reconstruct the object in the hand
okay and this is a very hard problem why
is it hard because you only see a few
pixels on that object and if you try to
do reconstruction with structure
promotion there's not going to be enough
of a variation in terms of Parallax or
disparity to do the Reconstruction the
best way to do the Reconstruction is to
use uh top down knowledge uh familiarity
with the category of the object to try
to do
reconstruction and uh so we built on
this model called MCC which was
presented last year at cvpr so this is a
a essentially a generic 3D fication uh
model which is that you given an image
and you have some object in it and that
object is being lifted to 3D from a
single image and uh this works okay for
certain classes of of objects and scen
but uh uh it's it's it's like the the
way it's not like solve the problem
fully it's not the setting that you can
say oh this is done we're done with this
but the belief is that over time uh
techniques like this will get better so
in particular what we wanted to do was
to adapt this
Machinery uh of doing 3D fication from a
single image to the case of an object in
the hand and object in the hand actually
offers some nice features because first
we can reconstruct the hand so the hand
is in 3D now and now you are
reconstructing the object in the context
of the hand so that defines a skin
because the object in that so the object
because human hands are always about the
same size so that gives you a notion of
scale like the distance between my thumb
and my forefinger is like 6 cm or
something right and you can guess that
just from the POS so if I'm holding this
object you get a size sense of the size
of this object because of the fact that
my thumb and four finger are in a
certain configuration
so the objects that humans are
manipulating we get a sense of their
size and shape from the fact that they
are in gter position with the human
hand okay and then additionally what you
can do is from your reconstruction which
in this case cases like a point Cloud
you can retrieve nearby models of
objects and then and then that does a
den noising in some ways so again the
usual thing where we say that our
approach is better than other people's
approach and uh uh which is fine uh but
again I view this as a as a problem on
which we have made substantial progress
but there is still more room to go but
this will happen in now in six months
from now one year from
now two years from now computer vision
will deliver on this problem computer
vision will give you good 3D hands it'll
give you good 3D objects it's up to the
roboticist to find a way to exploit this
because currently the work in robotics
essentially relies not on assuming that
this kind of a reconstruction is
possible okay so just to show what some
examples of successes so here we have
objects in the hand and the different
views are meant to show that uh that the
Reconstruction is actually in 3D
okay so uh so here so I'm going to stop
this here and uh again uh uh Now by
analogy with my previous talk where I
was talking about the whole body if so
now imagine so now let's indulgent
wishful thinking so let's imagine that
this 3D fication process is really
becomes really good and now we can aail
of the 156 million hours of video on you
YouTube or ego 4D or many of these other
data sets which show humans interacting
with
objects uh so that's uh okay this is
visual thinking it's not there yet but
uh as it but in research you have to
plan your research agenda assuming
things which are coming down the pipe
but uh so that's uh what will be the
problems we'll have to deal with I mean
just analogy to the previous talk where
if you you wanted to to have you have
humans walking and now you want to have
the atlas robot uh or the human doing a
cartwheel and you want the atlas robot
cartwheel so you have to solve the
retargeting problem and the way you
solve the retarget so you have to solve
the retargeting problem plus you have to
to deal with the physical Dynamics so
the way you deal with that is through uh
reinforcement learning in a physics
simulator so so one obvious remark here
is that there is an analog here so the
analog here is you take human
movements and the human hand movements
and then you put them on a robot hand so
you solve the retargeting problem and if
you do it in a physics simulator you can
you can deal with uh trying to uh solve
the deal with the physics part the
inverse
Dynamics okay that's one line of work
and there's been a lot of work in that
uh actually more work which is of the
type which is that we in we we don't
just download videos from YouTube rather
you have the human manipulate an object
in a in a in the lab and now you collect
data which is in the in the right
setting and you use that for for
retargeting so there's been a lot of
work like that the amount of work which
is really using vanilla videos
downloaded from uh YouTube is is
actually quite limited but again this to
me is a function of the technology as
the technology gets better we find more
use for it uh okay so that's at the
lowest level of the hierarchy where
you're trying to uh convert the
movements of the human hand into
movements of the robot hand ideally a
multi-fingered hand but as in the last
lecture there should be ways of
using these videos for information at
higher levels of abstraction and what
was it last time it was affordances and
sub routines so there should be a
counterpart to that here so let's look
at that so again the slide is from s
Gupta so there's a lowlevel uh in fact
mid level you can say sub routines and
affordances so we talked about that for
navigation but that should apply
here and then there should be uh even
higher level uh stuff which is okay
which is common sense about objects and
scenes so uh so this video uh right so
what what do we learn from this video
actually we learn a lot of things
here uh you have this video of a person
opening a cabinet what have you learned
let's think of what what kinds of things
have you learned so let me convert this
to a interactive session uh you you
watch a little clip of a human opening a
cabinet what have you learned which
could be useful for a
robot so the first
yeah okay good so that's one so there is
a common sense knowledge about the
cabinet okay that's good let's start
from the beginning of the video clip so
the first part what happened was that
the hand approached the cabinet and the
and then
what do you learn you learned how to
open the cabinet so how to open the
cabinet in this case you were not
turning something you held the handle
and you pull it towards you so this is
the affordance of the handle of the
cabinet door so you learned the
affordance of that okay if you think in
terms of sub routines what did you learn
you learned how to
grasp that object how to grasp that
handle so the human has a certain grip
grasp of the of the handle and then you
you move your arm so you learn that and
then you learn this Common Sense
knowledge about what are the objects
contained inside a cabinet so there's a
lot of
knowledge uh in in this little video
clip which is common sense knowledge and
motor control knowledge that that that
we can get yet I mean the small detail
is we don't know how to squeeze it out
but there is a lot of learning which one
can do from this video which we do not
yet know how to
do so this is like the grasp and then
you open and uh uh okay so so I'm now
going to take you through a few
representative papers which show what
what's being done these days in computer
vision and in robotics a lot of these
papers are in the some are in the
computer vision Community when you when
you at the end you don't get a robot to
do something you publish it in cvpr if
you get the robot to do something then
you submit it to a robotics
conference so uh uh but but I I I think
both are needed at this stage I think
this is totally okay so uh so what is
the Insight here what sites can we
interact at so that and then how to
interact with those sites so A and B is
basically about the affordance and then
and then you also acquiring a
trajectory so this is a paper from s of
gupta's group at
U so I got his b slides so we learn
through observation of human hands
interacting with the world okay so this
is just more slides which go through
this idea
uh okay attending to hands localizes and
stabilizes active objects hand show
where we can interact in the
scene analyzing hands reveals
information about objects their state
and how to interact with them so one
line of work which is sort of the
obvious one which I think we have papers
going back like five six years is is
essentially the hotspot what I call
hotpots line of work hotpots is
essentially where do you interact with
the object so when I look at so here's
this bottle if you see pictures of
people with bottles I mean this will be
a very typical interaction I do not go
around with the you know my finger the
bottle resting on my finger so people
essentially what are the interactions of
with this bottle there's this one and
let me and there is this one right so I
unscrewed the top and I so there is so
there's an affordance of the cap and
then there is how you carry and then how
you drink from it and all of these you
will observe in videos of people
interacting with water bottles so we a
robot so or a martian who comes to Earth
and wants to observe human behavior can
do that by just observing humans
right not similar water for
examplea drink because of the gas you
can drink
yeah so the affordances are different
because the content is different right
so so therefore this why I think
manipulation is harder than Locomotion
or navigation the range of affordances
we have to deal with is much
greater okay uh so uh let's see uh we
have lots and lots of data sets that the
computer vision Community has collected
which contain uh humans with hands
interacting with object so a very
important line of work is that from
David fy's Group which is on called 100
days of hands which is understanding
human hands in contact at internet
scales uh okay so so you can just find
lots and lots of pictures like this okay
so this is called a prismatic
grasp okay and uh and there has been
work on trying to use this for
self-supervised learning but I'm not
going to go into that okay this is an
example of this hotspot kind of work so
the hotspot kind of work is where do we
touch the object
okay and uh so that's indicated
here so like uh you don't you don't
touch the entire cabinet door you
typically touch it at the handle
okay uh you can also learn how how you
interact with objects so this is uh the
kind of grasp that you have for
different objects right so this is uh in
the grasping Community they call this
functional grasping as opposed to uh I
mean the previous style of grasping
research which was all about how to uh
stabilize an object so Force closure
grasps are about how to pick up an
object such that it doesn't fall down
here uh the way you pick up a mug uh I
mean there are at least three different
functional grasps I can think of if I
when I have a coffee mug and I want to
drink from it I lift it up from the
handle if the mug is uh dirty and I want
to put it in in the sink and I wash it I
have a different way in which I carry
the mug if I want to put the mug into
the dishwasher I will insert it in a
certain way when I want to take a clean
mug out from a dishwasher and put it on
my shelf I will interact with in a
different way so your classic robotic
solution of a force closure grasp is
kind of
meaningless or another example uh you're
sitting in a restaurant and then the
waiter brings you uh your glass of wine
and if he brings it with a force closure
grasp you will send him away you don't
want you don't want the the person's
Dirty Fingers in on your wi right so so
gasping is really ultimately in that
sense it becomes a learning problem okay
because uh we observe how humans
interact with object it's not just that
I mean there is obviously a part to do
with the physics which is stabilizing
the object and being robust to to
perturbation so so there is a part which
is physics related and there is a part
which is cultural so this is what makes
the problem challenging and interesting
and again there's a huge set of
techniques on how to uh you know infer
good grasping strategies and combination
of learning
simulation and uh classic robotic stuff
that I won't get into but I want to just
expose you to the fact that this is an
interesting
problem and then we uh yeah learn here
so these are all examples from this
paper from s gupta's group
okay uh I there are there is this other
trick which is a precursor to using the
video for training a robot which is that
uh you have a human interacting with
some objects in the environment and then
later on you want to have the robot
interact with the same objects and they
use this training for opening various
kinds of cabinet doors and they did a
real field experiment where you go to
different offices and kitchens and so on
and you open cabinet doors so the the
the problem is the following that the if
you want to use raw image data for
training then you're going to try to say
I want to copy this sequence of images
right so the robot is going to try to
move the robot hand in a way such that
you get that sequence of
images but the data is messed up because
the data has a human manipul in the
object so it has a human hand and
there's nothing that the robot can do to
make its hand look like a human hand so
therefore what you need to do is to
solve a factorization problem the
factorization problem is you have this
video this on the left oops
sorry what's happened here so uh so you
see this picture with this person's hand
on that plate with some salad or
something right
now what we want to do is to factorize
and remove the human hand from the
figure and have some kind of in painting
which completes the what the scene would
look like without the human so then the
robot can use that as the training
signal for the trajectories so these are
uh examples uh so one is some kind of
kitchen example another one is some kind
of a opening cabinets example and and
how do they do it uh you can okay
computer vision techniques you can make
use of the temporal history in some way
and uh so there is so what they've got
is this scene with the with the uh with
the objects of interest and the human
and then you separate it out into the
hand of the human and then what's the
environment minus the hands so the
robot's role is to deal with the the
second figure the sequence of
manipulations the changes that happen in
the
environment okay and so you are
segmenting out the hands from
the yeah yeah I mean well old school
done with new techniques so so they they
so of course there's a diffusion model
in here somewhere okay so there is a
video in
painting uh diffusion model and it makes
use of the temporal history and there's
some cross attention and you can read
this if you're interested but uh my
point was we use computer vision
Machinery to solve problems like this I
mean this is
not difficult for a computer vision
person to think of how to solve this
problem and uh and then uh and then you
can create these kinds of uh Missing now
the hand is missing so now the robot
basically has to try to uh copy the
sequence of transformations of the on
the in the environment
okay so sometimes the hand doesn't
completely disappear but mostly seems to
do a decent
job okay so the left is the real video
and then the right is the video minus
the human
hand okay so now this is minus the robot
hand in this
case Okay uh let
me uh okay so this is the use of yeah so
this is so this is essentially working
at a higher level of abstraction you're
working at the level of affordances and
in this case what you're doing is uh a
reward function so this goes back to the
de dense reward idea that I talked about
in the in the first lecture the sequence
of poses you try to copy each pose so in
this case it's not done in the 3D space
but 2D space
and uh they they they really use this
and to solve the problem of uh opening
draws so the claim is at U you see their
robots not to open
draws okay so now of course this is a
popular task in many of the systems but
uh I think what s's group did was uh is
the way I think testing should be done
is that they did the equivalent of mybnb
test for navigation so you go to some
place you haven't been before you take
your robot you put it down and you and
it has to open the draws as opposed to
very often in the kind of teleop data
that has been collected and then used in
Behavior cloning very often there are
subtle ways and you are overfitted to
the to the
tabletop where you have collected the
data I I mean testing properly I'm I'm
just saying good science good science
means good experimentation good
experimentation means that you need to
when you do your testing you you should
not have any uh you know contamination
from the training set so you just go you
have to if your robot can open drawers
you know you should go to your
grandmother 's house and have it open
draws if it can't do it that means you
you you it should not only work on the
eighth floor of ble Way West right I
mean we can collect data there and we
can make it work but it needs to work in
general if you're going to sell a home
robot for millions of people it has to
work in millions of
homes true but um feels like the field
kind of took a different approach just
punching everything so
like LM right just find and TR on
everything then yeah but I and now my my
belief is that uh I mean if you I don't
think you'll sell Many Robots if the
robot has to be fine tuned for for many
days to get anything real right when you
I I mean there whenever you have to do a
lot of work yourself to set up things
yeah uh like the old used to be I mean
you guys are all young so you don't know
this there used to be people used to
have VCRs which they used to record TV
shows and the old joke was nobody knew
how to program their VCR to record the
TV shows so every VCR would have some
flashing number which was that time
because the owner couldn't figure out
how to use it to record a TV show so if
you're robots are going to be like that
you're not going to invest $10,000 or
$220,000 in a robot it has to work when
you buy a dishwasher it works it doesn't
have to be fine tuned for your kitchen
and your your plates right
so okay uh and then we have some they
have some experiments which show that it
it learns faster this way uh okay uh let
me uh I have some slides which are which
are from let's see do I have the slides
in the wrong order yeah so so here's a
paper from Deepak pak's Group which I
liked which is on affordances is another
one of these affordance papers so there
was a whole family of papers from the
computer vision Community which are on
affordances and they basically amount to
find the hot spot from where humans are
interacting with it and then the local
trajectory which is what's the direction
in which the object should move uh and
here they capture it by uh with the help
of uh the some kind of a vector which
indicates a direction of movement so
that's what you abstract from the human
videos and then the robot tries to do
this so what I like about this paper
this uh you can I I I don't think I'm
going to click on it now because we're
going to run out of time uh is that they
they actually uh they show that uh uh
you can uh uh I mean have real robots
which can make use of these
affordances so this is a nice
paper uh and how does it work it works
with uh the top the left part is
learning Visual affordances and
deployment on robot so that high level
structure that I talked about in my
previous lecture which is you want
affordances and then you want sub
routines okay I think that that that
decomposition still makes sense so
affordances a we on the object object
and then what do you do afterwards which
is some kind of a trajectory of the
object's movement because the morphology
of the human hand and the robot hand are
different so the abstraction has to be
how does the object
move right so that's what they have here
theyve got some encoder trajectory
Network contact Point hip map trajectory
okay so that's the left part is what you
what you do at uh training time and then
the right part is how you uh you deploy
in a robot and they they manag to make
it work on real
robots Okay uh this is
the uh okay uh I should I try to click
this let me see if it
works no okay I have so let me use the
remaining 10 minutes to show some work
from imanu who's here uh on it's all in
this family of Recon inting 4 hand
object
interactions the we shouldn't have
music okay so so these are what kinds of
reconstruction we can do uh
okay again these are good examples as I
said the problem is
hard okay so uh so this is an example of
an effort in this tradiction and here
you're actually trying to learn from the
trajectories so what that means is that
you have to deal with the the
retargeting problem so the retargeting
problem is that the human hand is
different from the robot hand so you
have to find some way to get some
conversion and okay so you have a video
data set you have 3d hand object
trajectories and now you convert it to a
robot data set so you are trying to
transfer the human pose into a robot
pose
and now uh you have to get the right
movement so you can use inverse
kinematics for that right movement so
now you've got a whole bunch of
trajectories right and then these go
into uh into this uh again so the
Transformer causal Transformer idea
where you are doing next token
prediction we've already seen that
before so this is a a general trick
which is going to
work and uh and then then you uh okay
let's see so these are these are now
just some
demos so the the final part is if you
will fine tuned using uh using teleop BC
kind of stuff but on top of this
representation which has been trained on
on on video and uh if you don't do that
that if you have a relatively small
number of demonstrations then the
diffusion policy is uh is not so good
you see this shaky trajectory uh and you
get the benefit of this video experience
through
this pre-training
stage so this is one demo here's another
one
Iman do you want to add
any explanation or
I see this
is okay
okay yeah this is not this is not speed
it up
right yeah
[Music]
okay but our policy train all Theos and
then
okay uh let's see I I can show you one
more uh a paper there's a line of papers
from uh
uh deepak's group and uh also from
deepak's group at CMU and LEL Pinto
group at NYU and uh which are all in
this mode of okay trying to get some
robot policy with some learning from
humans and but very often the what is
done is that the human demonstration
which is being copied is in the lab and
in my mind that's not pure visual
imitation learning I want to be able to
get you know demos uh examples in the
wild the people whose videos are on
YouTube they did not do their task
thinking that somebody was going to do a
robot imitation so that to me is the is
the genuine version of the problem but I
think we are we are a ways there from
success on that so I I could show those
videos but there's some nice work from
these groups but I think it's fall shot
of this Grand goal of learning from raw
YouTube videos but uh with that I let's
throw the floor for uh questions
discussion we have I think 5 seven
minutes which I think we can use for
discussion
yeah that's what Tesla is trying
right so in theory uh so I I mean Tesla
has data I mean I don't know what Tesla
is exactly doing but theoretically they
have data on what what the cameras are
collecting and what drivers are doing
with respect to the steering and
acceleration and so on so certainly uh
the the earliest
examples so wait wait no this is not
visual imitation this is essentially
just this closer to behavior cloning in
fact the earliest example of policy
learning like this goes back to 1988 or
89 in CMU they tried to train uh this uh
uh their vehicle at that time to drive
and the way they did that was that they
collected images at low resolution like
32 by 32 pixels and then the driver
commands so they just recorded
that and then they use that
for neural network so this is I mean
we're talking about like 1990 right how
many years ago that's like uh 30 years
ago and uh and then there have been
versions of that done multiple times so
there's work done at Nvidia where they
have a front facing camera and then
cameras facing uh slightly off and then
the front facing camera gives you the
correct input and the side facing not
side but like 30° off cameras those are
used to essentially provide signal for
when you go slightly off how do you
correct but but that I would call that
in as following in the behavior cloning
paradigm not in visual
limitation which uh yeah so Fleet
learning
is
yeah it's best to have your test
environment I gu like looking into like
real robotics the past you see a lot of
things likeo hours mapping out your
environment I guess like why isn't there
more of the prevalence like I'll say
like this test time training like I feel
like there a lot of pap will do like
what you're talking about when you do
Behavior planing and then you like try
environment there's argument about like
in Conta system IDE there's not a lot of
work where you actually like train as
you go around yeah no I mean test time
training is totally fine I mean in the
sense that like the examples that I have
for navigation you take your mobile
robot and you put it down and then you
say go to a
TV okay it doesn't know the the
apartment so what's it going to do it's
going to explore to build a map to find
the TV so that is okay you expect your
robot to have to explore to build
something so but it should be a robust
procedure it's not that I'm trying to
find tune it to solve some basic
capability which should just be there it
should learn about a robot has to come
to your home and know the map learn the
map of your home I mean if you uh if you
employed a you know a butler or whatever
if you imagine that you are some rich
English Lord and you have a castle and
you employed a new uh you know uh
various uh staff like upstairs and down
downstairs kind of situation they would
have to acquire the knowledge about your
particular place so that's totally
okay the Environ and use it as like a
world model
have I mean more of approach for you
directly
kind yeah no some fine tuning is okay we
always become good at tasks with
practice so that is okay but you have to
be able to do a reasonable job in the
first
instance yeah I mean I shouldn't have to
train you to use my knives if you go to
a friend's house and you're helping them
cook dinner and they say okay can you
chop the onions you don't say okay give
me a five minute tutorial on how to use
your knives
right so we always I mean uh I don't
know suppose you you you rent a bike and
there's a different bike from the one
that you have ridden before you're going
to do like a few seconds of adaptation
before you get used to the controls and
uh the compliance of that bike and
that's totally
okay uh it's just that when more is
required that essentially implies that
you didn't really solve the
problem more
questions
comments okay we can end thank you